Guide to the Committee on the Architectural Plan, Yale University Corporation, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on the Architectural Plan, Yale University Corporation, records
1913-1931
RU 30
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The records consist of correspondence, blueprints and tables, clippings, and publications maintained by John V. Farwell as chairman of the Committee on the Architectural Plan.
Yale Corporation
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 1-B (YRG 1-B), Records of Yale Corporation committees.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject, with correspondence subdivided chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
In the early 1900s, Anson Phelps Stokes, secretary, and George Parmly Day, treasurer, won Corporation approval for the preparation of a general architectural plan for Yale University. Mrs. Frances P. Garvan, a benefactor of Yale, secured and offered the services of architect John Russell Pope. Pope's plan served as the stimulus for the general plan of the University which was adopted in 1924, after study and revision by the Corporation's Committee on the Architectural Plan and James Gamble Rogers, consulting architect to Yale.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, blueprints and tables, clippings, and publications maintained by John V. Farwell as chairman of the Committee on the Architectural Plan.
Architecture -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Campus planning -- Connecticut -- New Haven; College buildings; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Farwell, John Villiers, 1858-1944; Pope, John Russell, 1874-1937; Rogers, James Gamble, 1867-1947; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Planning; Yale Corporation
- Committee on Architectural Plan records, Accession 1932-A-007
  - Papers of John N. Farwell as Chairman, 1913-1931
    - Blueprints and Tables, 1917, 1922, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 12)
      - 1924 [McClellan Hall] (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 15)
      - 1927-1931 (Box 2, Folder 16 - 23)
    - University Publications, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 24)